FILIPA BRITO

MARKETING / PROJECT MANAGER

Rua de S. Brás 357, 4000-496 Porto, PT **T:** +351 927 501 122

E: filipabrito.a@gmail.com

PROFILE

Creative, analytical and strategic project manager with over 8 years experience managing various multidiscipline teams and developing effective brands that inspire. Specialised in internationalisation/expansion and marketing management.

Digital native, always eager to learn more. Deadline driven, able to multi-task as needed to ensure projects are completed on-time and on-budget and to maintain a sense of humor under pressure. Work well with both leading and within a team. Available to embrace projects worldwide.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mar 2015 -Jun 2020

Project Manager - Expansion / Brand / Digital

Typographia, Oporto, PT

Dynamic role in which I was responsible for planning and coordinating multiple multidiscipline projects, teams and budgets of up to 2M€. Reported

Expansion - Opening of 5 new stores and renovation of 3 existing ones. Establish wholesale business to museums. Create new B2B brand. Etc.

Brand - Develop brand/marketing strategy through digital and physical channels. Coordinate team/agencies on content creation. Establish product collaborations. Digital - Develop new website and e-commerce shop. Manage e-commerce

operations, team, customer service and product development.

Jun 2014 -Nov 2014

District Manager

Lidl, North Region, PT

Training period where I coordinated teams of 10 to 20 people in multiple stores. I was also responsible for monitoring store performance, optimize processes and address lapses in compliance with policies and national laws.

Mar 2012 -May 2014

Marketing Specialist & Marketing Director's Assistant

Covet Group, Oporto, PT

Implement multi-brand digital and physical marketing strategies for the UK market. Assist marketing director in the development of the group's marketing plan, coordinate team of 50 people and organize events and trade

EDUCATION

Sept 2008 -

Bachelor of Business Administration

Jun 2012

University of Oporto, Oporto, PT

Mathematics, Statistics, Marketing, Econometrics, Corporate Strategy,

Economics, Accounting, Corporate Finance.

AIESEC - Marketing Director '10 | AEFEP - Marketing Coordinator '11

Jan 2011 -

Jul 2011

Bachelor of Business Administration

University Autonoma de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain

Exchange Program (ERASMUS).

Sept 2015 -Jun 2017

Master in International Business

University of Oporto, Oporto, PT

International Marketing, International Strategic Management,

Multinationals and Internationalisation.

SKILLS

CORE

Lean/Agile Project Management

Decision Making Leadership **Brand Positioning**

Data Analysis

TECH

Google Analytics Excel Adobe Photoshop SEO/SEM HTML, CSS & JS Python • • 0 0 0

LANGUAGES

Native Portuguese C2 (FCE 2008) English

Spanish

CERTIFICATES

Project Management Professional (PMP)®

PMI, In course

Content Marketing

Hubspot Academy, Nov 2020

Advanced Google Analytics

Google, Oct 2020

Agile Foundations

Linked In, Oct 2020

ACHIEVEMENTS

100% revenue growth

Typographia, PT

10K+ organic followers on IG

Typographia, PT



in filipabrito